A Guide to the Correspondence and Subject Files of the Virginia Secretary of Education, 1975-1997.
Library of Virginia
Library of Virginia
Education, Virginia Secretary of, Correspondence and Subject files
1975-1997.
The Library of Virginia
31310, 32012, 32651, 34742, 35868, 37781
Virginia. Secretary of Education
116 cubic feet
Biographical/Historical Information
In 1970, the Governor's Management Commission Study recommended the creation of six "Deputy Governors" assist the Chief Executive in his managerial duties, compatible functions of government were grouped under these administrative heads, who would serve as the Governor's top management team or "secretariats," as they are called now. The General Assembly in 1972 created six Secretariats positions initially. As government reorganized, that number fluctuated when government agencies expanded or consolidated.
The Secretary of Education assists the Governor in the development and implementation of the state's education policy. The secretary provides guidance to 16 colleges and universities, the Virginia Community College System, five higher education and research centers, the Department of Education, the state-supported museums, and other agencies in the Education Secretariat. All secretaries are appointed by the governor and serve at his will.
Scope and Content
The correspondence and subject files of the Secretary of Education document the development, establishment and implementation of educational and cultural policy in the Commonwealth. These files consist of incoming and outgoing correspondence with the Governor's Office, state and federal agencies, educational institutions, and the private sector; reports, minutes, memoranda, budget documents, legislative materials and other related materials.
Various arrangements. Records have been kept in their original order.
Acquisition Information
Accession 31310 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, January 14, 1982.
Accession 32012 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, XX.
Accession 32651 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, February 18, 1986.
Accession 34742 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, XX.
Accession 35868 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, June 16, 1998.
Accession 37781 was transferred by the Virginia Secretary of Education, XX.
Contents List
- Secretary's correspondence and subject files (Accession 31310), 1980., Extent: 6 cubic feet (3 boxes)
  - Commission for the Arts, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Community Colleges, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Western Community College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - WVWR Radio Station, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Germanna Community College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Western Campus - Goochland, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Education, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 1)
  - State Council on Higher Education, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Council of Visitors, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Science Museum, 1980. (Box 1)
  - State Education Assistance Authority, 1980. (Box 1)
  - State Library, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Museum, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Christopher Newport College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Clinch Valley College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - George Mason Univerity, 1980. (Box 1)
  - International Law School, 1980. (Box 1)
  - James Madison University, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Longwood College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Mary Washington College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Norfolk State College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Old Dominion University, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Radford University, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Radford University, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Richard Bland College, 1980. (Box 1)
  - University of Virginia, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Associated Research Campus, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Virginia Commonwealth University / Virginia Community College System Computer Center, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Military Institute, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia State University, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Truch and Ornamentals Research Station, 1980. (Box 2)
  - College of William and Mary, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Sicence (VIMS), 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Staunton, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Hampton, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind - Board, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped (general), 1980. (Box 2)
  - Developmental Disabilities and Protection Advocacy Office, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Identification and Diagnosis of Children Who Are Handicapped, 1980. (Box 2)
  - MASC, 1980. (Box 2)
  - ACEC, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - AACJC, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Apiculture, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Appropriations Committee, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Attorney General, 1980. (Box 2)
  - B - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - BRAVO Arts Education, 1980. (Box 2)
  - C- Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Chamber of Commerce, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Children, Division of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Comptroller, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Computer Services, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - D - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Deaf, Virginia Council, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Education Commission for the States, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Eminent Scholars Program, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Enrollment, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Excellence, Center of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - F - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - G- Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - General Services, Div. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - General Assembly, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Governor's School for the Gifted, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Grants, 1980. (Box 2)
  - H - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Health, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 2)
  - I - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Independent Colleges, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Indirect Costs, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Indo-Chinese Refugees, 1980. (Box 2)
  - J - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1980. (Box 2)
  - Jacques Cousteau Society, 1980. (Box 2)
  - K - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - L - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Land Grant Colleges and State Universities Association, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Libraries, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Legislative Fiscal Impact Statements, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Legislative Implementation Reports, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Legislative Summary, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Legislation Proposed, 1980. (Box 3)
  - M - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Monthly Mileage Reports, 1980. (Box 3)
  - N - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Nursing (Programs/Salaries), 1980. (Box 3)
  - Organizational memberships, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Out-of-County Travel, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Out-of-State Travel, 1980. (Box 3)
  - P - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Poet Laureate, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Positions, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Presidential Scholars Program, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Property values, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Q - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - R - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Refugee Resettlement, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Rehabilitation Act / Sections 503 and 504, 1980. (Box 3)
  - S - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Service Charges (Properties in Virginia Beach), 1980. (Box 3)
  - Society to Prevent Blindness, 1980. (Box 3)
  - SOLINET (library networking), 1980. (Box 3)
  - T - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - U - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Office of Education, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Veterans Administration, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Forum on Education, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Foundation for Humanities and Public Policy, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Graduate Marine Science Consortium, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia High School League, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Virginia Public School Authority, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Vocational Education, Virginia State Advisory, 1980. (Box 3)
  - W - Miscellaneous, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Planning and Budget, Dept. of, 1980. (Box 3)
  - Office of Education (general), 1980. (Box 3)
  - Office of Education (budget), 1980. (Box 3)
- Secretary's correspondence and subject files (Accession 32012), 1977-1981., Extent: 21 cubic feet (21 boxes)
  - C - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Campus housing, 1981. (Box 1)
  - CETA - Comprehensie Employment and Training Act, 1981. (Box 1)
  - CETA - Comprehensive Employment and Training Act, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Chamber of Commerce, State, 1982. (Box 1)
  - Chamber of Commerce, State, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Climatologist, State, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Climatologist, State, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Climatologist, State, 1979. (Box 1)
  - College Building Authority, Virginia, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Commonwealth Assistance Fund, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Competency testing, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Competence testing, 1980. (Box 1)
  - Comptroller, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Computer Services, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Conflict of Interest, 1979-1980. (Box 1)
  - Congressional Award, 1981. (Box 1)
  - D- Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Deaf, Virginia Council for the, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Duplication and Undue Competition Task Force on the Elimination of, 1981. (Box 1)
  - E - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Eastern Virginia Medical Authority, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Education Commission of the States (ECS) - Annual meeting, 1981 Jan. (Box 1)
  - Education (General) - Newsclippings, 1979-1982. (Box 1)
  - Eminent Scholars, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Energy (Emergency and Energy Services), 1981. (Box 1)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of, 1982 Jan. (Box 1)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of - Directives, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Engineering and Buildings, Division of - Surplus land, 1981. (Box 1)
  - Dept. of Education - General correspondence, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Education - Personnel, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Education - Special Education, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Education - Vocational Education, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Education - Teacher certification, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Dept. of Education - Superintendent of Public Instruction, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - Federal Regional Council, 1978. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - American Association for Public Administration, Virginia Report, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - Programs/Funding, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - Federal State Aid, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - Agency notification of intent, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs - Federal Funds Report (Summary of receipts by state agencies), 1978. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Identification and diagnosis of children who are handicapped, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Handicapped children in state operated facilities, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Overall Advisory Council on the Needs of Handicapped Children and Adults, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Virginia Schools Merged Board, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind (Staunton), 1981. (Box 2)
  - Handicapped - Virginia School for the Deaf and Blind (Hampton), 1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Cooperative Extension Guidelines Task Force, 1978-1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Extension Division, 1977. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Task Force on Positions, 1978-1979. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Veterinary School, 1981. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Veterinary School, 1980. (Box 2)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Veterinary School, 1979. (Box 2)
  - Biracial Committee, 1979. (Box 3)
  - Biracial Committee - Meeting, 1980 Jan. (Box 3)
  - Biracial Committee - Meetings, 1980 Dec. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1977. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1978. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1979. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1980. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1981. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare, 1982. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare - Texas, 1981. (Box 3)
  - U.S. Dept. of Health, Education and Welfare - Title IX, 1975. (Box 3)
  - Bakke Case, 1978-1979. (Box 3)
  - A Plan for Equal Opportunity in Virginia's Institutions of Higher Learning: A Shared Response, 1974 Feb. (Box 3)
  - A Reformation of the Plan for Equal Opportunity in Virginia's Institutions of Higher Learning: A Shared Response, 1977 Sept. (Box 3)
  - A - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 3)
  - Agriculture and Consumer Services, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 3)
  - Aircraft - State Owned, 1980-1981. (Box 3)
  - American Association of Community and Junior Colleges, 1981. (Box 3)
  - American Council on Education, 1981. (Box 3)
  - Applicants, 1979-1981. (Box 3)
  - Appropriation Committee, 1981. (Box 3)
  - ARTS Program, 1980-1981. (Box 3)
  - Attorney General, 1981. (Box 3)
  - B - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 3)
  - Bravo Arts Education, 1981. (Box 3)
  - Comptroller, Office of the, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Cultural agencies, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Developmental Disabilities Planning Council, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Division for Children, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Emergency and Energy Services, 1981. (Box 4)
  - State Education Assitance Authority, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Legislative summaries, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Council on the Environment, 1980. (Box 4)
  - State Employees Credit Union, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Fire Services Commission, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of General Services, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Highways and Transportation, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Housing and Community Development, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1979-1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Museum of Fine Arts, 1980-1982. (Box 4)
  - Division of Justice and Crime Prevention, 1981. (Box 4)
  - State Library, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Museum and History Federation, 1977-1980. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Personnel and Training, 1976-1977. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Retirement System, 1979. (Box 4)
  - Science Museum of Virginia, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Secretary of the Commonwealth, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Telecommunications Council, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Treasury, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Dept. of Welfare, 1980. (Box 4)
  - Non-State Agencies, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Personellite, 1982. (Box 4)
  - Equal Opportunity and Higher Education, 1982. (Box 4)
  - Report of Education Research, 1982. (Box 4)
  - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1977. (Box 4)
  - Legislation: Federal legislation, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Legislation: Drafted legislation, 1981. (Box 4)
  - Legislation: Drafted legislation, 1982. (Box 4)
  - Legislation: Propsed legislation, 1982. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Progress Report on Legislative Studies, 1982-1983. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative process, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Division on Legislative Services, 1978-1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative Studies, 1982. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative Studies, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: HB 1011, 1980. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative Studies - Cumulative listing, 1980. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative Implementation Report, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Legislative References, 1980-1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: HJR 239 - State Library Networking System, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Joint Subcommittee on Minimum Competency Testing / Handicapped, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: SJR 132 - Legislative Study on Developmental Guidance and Counseling in Elementary Schools, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: HJR 97 - Vocational, Technical and Career Education, 1980. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Recommendations to the Governor, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: SJR 179 - Committee on Special Education Teachers, 1979. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Agency initiated, 1981. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Recommendations to the Governor on Enrolled Bills, 1979. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Requests for Budget Bill amendments, 1979. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Hopkins Commission, 1974-1979. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: HB 2164 - Freedom of Information Act, 1977. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Federal Education Legislation, 1977. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Federal Public Laws, 1965-1968. (Box 5)
  - Legislation: Articles of Interest, 1974. (Box 5)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Veterinary School, 1978. (Box 6)
  - Virginia Polytechnic Institute and State University - Veterinary School, 1977. (Box 6)
  - Virginia State University, 1982. (Box 6)
  - Virginia State University, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Virginia Truck and Ornamentals Research Station, 1981. (Box 6)
  - College of William and Mary, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of, 1978-1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Directives (1-80), 1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Directives (2-80), 1980. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Exeception to MUP (Directive 3-80), 1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Directives (5-80), 1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Directives (6-80 - Cash Management), 1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Directives, 1978-1981. (Box 6)
  - Administration and Finance, Secretary of: Assistant for Financial Policy (Connock), 1981. (Box 6)
  - Secretary of Public Safety, 1978-1981. (Box 6)
  - Management Analysis and Systems Development, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Advisory Council for Educational Computing, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Personnel and Training, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 6)
  - Presidential salaries, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Leave and sick leave policies in institutions of higher learning, 1979. (Box 7)
  - Presidential leave, 1979. (Box 7)
  - Faculty salaries, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Faculty salaries, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Task Force on Overregulation, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Ad Hoc Committee on Resource Materials (BDS/Visitors), 1980. (Box 7)
  - Presidential guidelines, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Employment and compensations of presidents, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Calculating FTE faculty - Full and part time, 1980-1981. (Box 7)
  - Developmental Education Study, 1981. (Box 7)
  - State Council of Higher Education for Virginia (SCHEV) - Staff reorganization proposal, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Enrollment - Higher education institutions, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Maintenance of excellence, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Maintenance of excellence, 1980. (Box 7)
  - LAB Schoool, 1980-1981. (Box 7)
  - Council of Visitors, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Survey - Boards of Visitors, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Roles and responsibilities - College and university governing boards, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Science Museum, 1981. (Box 7)
  - State Education Assistance Authority, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Virginia State Library, 1980. (Box 7)
  - Virginia State Library, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Virginia Associated Research Campus, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Space radiation - VARC, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Virginia Education Loan Authority, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Virginia Institute of Marine Science, 1981. (Box 7)
  - Tidewater Library Network Study - Final Report, 1978. (Box 7)
  - Review of Police / Security Dept. at the Virginia Museum of Fine Arts (VMFA), 19. (Box 7)
  - Fact file - Chronicle of Higher Education, 1978. (Box 8)
  - Federal budget cuts, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Federal block grants, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Virginia Association of Independent Schools, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Federal budgets (President FY 1981), 1980. (Box 8)
  - Regulatory relief - Federal, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Federal rules and regulations, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Financial aid (automated system), 1981. (Box 8)
  - 4-H Center at Wakefield, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Furniture, State Office Advisory Committee, 1981. (Box 8)
  - G - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - General Assembly, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Grievance procedures, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Governor's Conference on Library and Information Service, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Governor's School for the Gifted, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Governing Boards, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Governing Boards, 1980. (Box 8)
  - Governing Boards - Orientation workshop for new board members, 1980. (Box 8)
  - Governing Boards - Board member workshop, 1979. (Box 8)
  - Governing Boards - Governor's orientation workshop and luncheon, 1978. (Box 8)
  - H - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Health Dept., 1981. (Box 8)
  - I - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Impact aid, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Incentive awards, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Incentive payments for agency heads, 1980. (Box 8)
  - Independent colleges, 1982. (Box 8)
  - Independent colleges, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Independen Colleges, Council on, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Independent schools, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Indirect costs, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Intergovernmental Affairs, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 8)
  - J - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Joint Legislative Audit and Review Commission (JLARC), 1981. (Box 8)
  - Jacques Cousteau Society, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Justice and Crime Prevention, Divison, 1981. (Box 8)
  - K - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - L - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 8)
  - Legislation, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Legislative contacts, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Agency reports to General Assembly, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Proposed legislation, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Impact statements, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Legislation, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Legislative summary, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Legislative impact statements, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Agency / Institution legislative proposals, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Legislation - Legislative process, 19. (Box 9)
  - M - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Minority Business Enterprise Program, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Monthly mileage reports, 1981. (Box 9)
  - National Governors Association, 1982. (Box 9)
  - National Governors Association, 1981. (Box 9)
  - National Graduate University, 1981. (Box 9)
  - O - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Out of country travel requests, 1982. (Box 9)
  - Out of country travel, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Out of state travel, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Organizational memberships, 1981. (Box 9)
  - P- Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Partners of the Americas, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Publications - State, 1981. (Box 9)
  - Purchases and Supply, 1980. (Box 9)
  - R- Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Regional Computer Technology School Committee, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Regulatory Council's report, US, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Rehabilitative School Authority, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Revenue estimates (Gov. John Dalton statement), 1981. (Box 10)
  - Risk Management Office of, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Rules and Regulations Issued during FY 1979-1980 by Education Agencies, 1981. (Box 10)
  - S - Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Senate Finance, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Senate Joint Resolution 20 (Agriculture), 1981. (Box 10)
  - Service charges, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Southern Governor's Association, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB), 1981. (Box 10)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB) - Legislative workshops, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Southern Regional Education Board (SREB) - Meeting, 1981. (Box 10)
  - T- Miscellaneous, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Teacher competency, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Teacher grievances, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Telecommunications, Dept. of, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Transition, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Travel, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Travel correspondence, 1980. (Box 10)
  - Tuition, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Tuition (service members), 1982. (Box 10)
  - Tuition (service members), 1981. (Box 10)
  - Unsung Virginians, 1981. (Box 10)
  - U.S. Dept. of Education, 1981. (Box 10)
  - United Way Campaign, 1981. (Box 10)
  - University of Richmond, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Association of Independent Schools, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Cultural Laureate, 1981. (Box 10)
  - Virginia Education Association, 1981. (Box 11)
  - Virginia Employment Commission, 1981. (Box 11)
  - Virginia Executive Development Institute, 1981. (Box 11)
  - Virginia Forum on Education, 1981. (Box 11)